# **CEVI HERDIAN**

# Data Analyst & Business Intelligence Enthusiast

# **Curriculum Vitae**

#### **Personal information**

Name: Cevi Herdian

Address: Coppistr. 16, 10365, Berlin

Phone: +4917632811289 Mail: itsmecevi@gmail.com

An Enthusiast in Data Analyst & Business Intelligence. Practiced Data Analyst with more than 3 years of experience in extraction, transformation, loaded, statistical interpreting and visualizing various types of dataset. Focusing on KPI Dashboard (Key Performance Indicator) and Predictive Analytics.

- My personal web: <a href="https://itsmecevi.github.io/">https://itsmecevi.github.io/</a>
- My work and ideas in order: https://itsmecevi.github.io/cevipedia/
- My web about Data Visualization & Analytics: https://itsmecevi.github.io/dataviz-kpi/#

#### **Experience**

October 2016 - Present:

## Data Analyst & Business Intelligence Developer HTW Berlin-University of Applied Sciences, working student

- Data extraction (ETL process) from different sources such as Excel, Access, SaaS (Software as a Service), Web Service, and from a Database (SQL)
- Developing live stream on-premise and web-based KPI
  Dashboard (Key Performance Indicators) for Federal Statistical
  Office of Germany and for internally used at Human Resources,
  Finance, IT, and Research Department of HTW Berlin
- Ad-Hoc Reporting (Web-based & On-premise)

April 2016 - August 2016:

#### Data Analyst TradeMachines GmbH, working student

- Collecting machinery data from all website over the world with Web Scraping machine
- Creating all about Data Mining workflow such as preparing, cleaning, formatting, modeling, anomaly detection, classification (without clustering), normalize, and training the dataset of all machinery items for big data environment

April 2015 - December 2015:

### Business Data Analyst Omnea GmbH, internship & working student

- Financial and Managerial Accounting
- Developing Financial, Managerial, Marketing, and Sales KPI Dashboard (Key Performance Indicator) for internal users and investor

# **Education**

April 2016 - Present: HTW Berlin-University of Applied Sciences

Master of Science - Financial Services & Risk Management

Business Data Analyst Track

April 2012 - May 2016:

HTW Berlin-University of Applied Sciences Bachelor of Science - Business Mathematics

Business Data Analyst Track



# **CEVI HERDIAN**

# Data Analyst & Business Intelligence Enthusiast

April 2011 - December 2011: Studientkolleg, HTW Berlin-University of Applied Science

Higher education entrance qualification (A-levels)

**Natural Sciences** 

Goethe Institute Indonesia & Hartnackschule Berlin August 2010 - March 2011:

German courses

#### Award

June 2009: June 2009: October 2009:

June 2010 - December 2015: Full Scholarships - Subang Germany Scholarships - Indonesia Top 10 - International Physics Olimpiad - West Java Division 1st Place - International Physics Olimpiad - Subang Division

Top 10 - Chemistry Olimpiad - West Java, 2009

## **Certification & training**

August 2015-Present:

## **Data Analyst & Business Intelligence:**

Microsoft Professional Program - Data Science

Microsoft Office Specialist (MOS) Excel

Microsoft Power BI

Data Analyst & BI MOOC in Lynda.com, Edx.com, Coursera.com

ScrumStudy.com: Scrum Fundamental Certified

Datacamp.com: R programming

All certifications link: https://itsmecevi.gitbook.io/cert/

# Key Skill

I adapt to new concepts and software quickly. Practicing in several methods and software, such as:

Microsoft Excel

Power Query & Mashup (M Language)

Data Model, DAX, Power Pivot

Power View & Power Maps

Macro-VBA

Microsoft Access & SQL

Microsoft Power BI (on premise & web-based)

R programming & Shiny app (R web-based)

Data Analyst:

o Descriptive & Inferential Statistics

Time series & Predictive Analytics

Key Performance Indicator (KPI)

Basic Version Control System with Github

Project Management Know How

## **Pro Bono**

2012 - 2013 2011

Mathematics Tutor, IWKZ e.V.

Member of Education Department PPI Berln e.V.

# Language

Indonesian German & English

Native Intermediate